Contact

victor.tolbert@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/victortolbert (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Node.js Responsive Web Design Git

Certifications

Staying Sharp with Angular.js

Victor Tolbert

Senior Front-End/UI Developer

Atlanta, Georgia, United States

Summary

Accomplished front-end web developer with extensive experience working with high profile companies and organizations; Proficient with HTML, CSS and modern JavaScript; an in-depth understanding of SEO and site performance optimization; skilled analytical problem-solver with the ability to quickly learn new technologies; polished communication, presentation, training and client relations skills; able to relate effectively to people at all levels and convey complex technical information in an understandable manner.

Experience

Hancock Claims Consultants
Software Engineer
May 2021 - Present (2 years 9 months)

VTi Consulting
Owner
May 2002 - Present (21 years 9 months)
Atlanta Metropolitan Area

Design and develop standards-compliant, user-centered web sites, and applications for small businesses and non-profit organizations

Provide and have provided a broad range of IT services (design, development, operations, and consulting) as a corp-to-corp / non-employee partner for numerous for-profit and non-profit companies and organizations including AT&T, the Urban League of Greater Atlanta (ulgatl.org), and for All About Developmental Disabilities (aadd.org)

Host, administer and maintain email, database, and web servers (Apache and nginx)

Booster
1 year 11 months

Senior Web Developer

May 2019 - August 2020 (1 year 4 months)

Alpharetta, Georgia, United States

JavaScript Developer

October 2018 - May 2019 (8 months)

Greater Atlanta Area

- Participate in the design and development process from definition to deployment.
- Work closely with the design team to ensure consistent UI/UX implementations.
- Assist team in managing the overall codebase and infrastructure.
- Implement best practices and new solutions to create a scalable innovative application.

Turner Sports

Senior Front-end Web Developer

February 2018 - October 2018 (9 months)

Greater Atlanta Area

Videa, LLC

Senior UI Architect / UX Designer

June 2014 - November 2017 (3 years 6 months)

Greater Atlanta Area

Worked with product managers to define, design and build front-end user interface prototypes. Developed and maintained the UI standards and design best practices. Participated in all UI testing activities.

AT&T

Senior HTML5 UI Developer

February 2013 - June 2014 (1 year 5 months)

Greater Atlanta Area

- Provide user interface development for a project to integrate the AT&T Locker, Messages and Contacts cloud applications into one unified consumer application suite.
- Project focuses on Web and Tablet HTML5 applications and services.
- Responsible for developing the Dashboard application to login & register users and provision & launch applications.

WebMD

Web Developer

July 2010 - December 2012 (2 years 6 months)

- Collaborated with product managers, designers, web publishers, and producers to build and implement sponsored revenue products, modules and widgets using Agile/SCRUM methodology
- Hand-coded and documented modular website components using objectoriented native JavaScript and jQuery
- Team lead for key revenue generating products and initiatives
- Converted a Flash-based widget for iPhone/iPad compatibility using HTML5,
 CSS3 and JavaScript
- Mentored and on-boarded new team members
- Maintained and managed multiple projects and consistently met tight deadlines

AutoTrader.com
User Interface Engineer
November 2005 - July 2010 (4 years 9 months)
Greater Atlanta Area

- Assisted team in the creation of interface design standards, and provided guidance on web accessibility and usability
- Created and maintained dynamic user interface templates for the web site and supporting applications
- Actively partnered with project team members in identifying usability issues and made recommendations
- Worked with project managers to understand business objectives, provided technical assessments, UI recommendations, risk analysis, and accurate development estimates
- Stayed current with web standards, application architectures, and deployment techniques
- Maintained UNIX-based development environment to support multiple applications and Apache web server configurations

WebMD

UI Designer / Web Developer November 2003 - October 2005 (2 years)

- Worked with graphics design group and senior producers to develop fullscale HTML projects
- Ensured accessibility against supported browser matrix
- · Prototyped new information architecture for web site redesign
- · Performed user testing for new web site structure

• Created an intranet portal to chronicle development progress and to facilitate development discussions

Witness Systems User Interface Designer/Usability Specialist

2000 - 2002 (2 years)

- Developed detailed mockups and HTML prototypes to effectively communicate design ideas
- Member of task force to evaluate and establish an n-tiered development architecture
- Performed heuristic and usability evaluations
- Created user flow diagrams, wireframes, site maps, flowcharts, storyboards, and rapid prototypes for clients and engineering team
- Worked with multidisciplinary teams (creative, technical, strategic) to produce a cohesive look and feel

SideTalk.com

Web Developer

May 2000 - August 2000 (4 months)

- Maintained consumer web site content and updates
- Front-end development and UI design
- Member of 12-person technology team credited with the design and implementation of company Web site and an innovative 'co-browsing' web application
- Acquired by Witness Systems, August 2000

The Coca-Cola Company

Senior Systems Support Specialist

1995 - 1998 (3 years)

- Installed and supported Lotus Notes based sales force automation system for about 800 users
- Provided one-on-one software training for clients
- Served as an effective Team Leader and liaison between Technical Support Group and management
- Deemed as one of the most successful initiatives achieving a 95% exceptional rating among users
- Provided 2nd level PC and Macintosh software and hardware support for over 1000 IS and Legal Clients
- Identified as company wide subject matter expert (SME) for Corel and Adobe products

 \bullet Assisted with special projects, including migration from Windows v3.1 to Windows 95

Education

Morehouse College

Bachelor of Arts - BA, Business Administration and Management, General